谢尔顿·库珀的发疯之路
Sheldon Cooper's descent into madness...
第二天
day two.
现在是深夜2点25
It's 2:25 A.M.,
我有一股强烈的尿意
and I feel the urge to urinate.
我正常的晨尿时间是早上7点10分
My normal urination time is 7:10 A.M.,
但在这夜半时刻
but here I am, in the middle of the night,
我却挣扎着要保持头脑清晰
struggling to keep my mind sharp
与睡衣裤干燥
and my pajamas dry.
迟早有一天
It's only a matter of time
我对现实薄弱的掌握力就会消失
before my tenuous grasp on reality fades.
还是趁没忘记什么是厕所前  赶紧去尿吧
I suppose I should pee while I still know what a toilet is.
你什么时候开始哼歌了
Since when do you hum songs?
你说啥呢
What are you talking about?
你刚才在哼歌
You were just humming.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
有时候当我脑筋运转飞快
Sometimes when my brain really gets moving,
也会发出声音
it makes noise.
那你的大脑对于
How does your brain feel about
计算畴壁的表面张力怎么看
calculating the surface tension of the domain walls?
我看看
Let's see.
我还真是在哼歌
Hey! I was humming.
赫奇帕奇加一分
One point for Hufflepuff.
小说《哈利波特》中的学院名
该学院学生多为勤能补拙型的学生
这是什么歌啊
What song is that?
你再哼一次
Well... Hum it again.
是《海绵宝宝》的主题曲吗
Is that the SpongeBob song?
♪  是谁住在深海的大凤梨里 ♪
♪  Who lives in a pineapple? ♪
不是
Nope.
随便啦  能回到正题吗
Whatever. Can we just get back to this?
我总感觉我知道这首歌
I feel like I know what song that is,
但就是想不起是哪一首
but I can't put my finger on it.
♪  爱吾土兮自由乡 ♪
♪  My country, 'tis of thee ♪
不是
No.
只是歌曲卡脑里[耳虫]了  会想起来的
It's just an earworm. It'll come to you.
好吧
Okay.
♪  酋寸千日土 ♪
♪  R-e-s-p-e-c-t ♪
不是
No.
我们今晚余下时间都要这样吗
Is this what we're doing the rest of the night?
♪  我很惊讶你居然还问... ♪
♪  I'm surprised you have to ask... ♪
翻译：赛太公私奔到月球  YY猫留在地球
月亮之上猫中之王
您好  是的  我希望你们能帮一下我
Hello, yes, I was hoping you could help me.
这首歌是什么歌呢
What song is this?
你不知道吗
You don't know?
你们怎么好意思称自己为"摇滚名人堂"呢
Well, how dare you call yourselves a Rock and Roll Hall of Fame?
我的老天  你就是用这张脏嘴来
My goodness. Do you sing along to the greatest hits
跟唱猫王的传世杰作吗
of Elvis Presley with that mouth?
他们一点屁用都没有
Well, they were no help at all.
真"不敢置信"啊
Which is crazy,
毕竟摇滚最讲究良好的客户服务了
since rock and roll is all about good customer service.
你脑子里卡了一首歌
Yeah. So you have a song stuck in your head.
这在大家身上都发生过啊
It happens to everybody.
我不是大家  我有过目不忘的记忆力
Well, I'm not everybody. I have an eidetic memory.
我应该要能记住这是哪首歌的
I should be able to remember what song this is,
可我就是想不起来
but I can't.
我脑子肯定哪里有问题
Something's wrong with me.
我就说如果我们够耐心  他会自己发现这事
I told you if we were patient, he'd figure it out for himself.
我从以前就很害怕这天的到来
Oh... I was always afraid this day would come.
这可能是我变成疯子的第一步
This might be the first step of my descent into madness,
然后我逐步探底直至在公众场合裸露
where I gradually test the limits of public nudity.
公众场合裸露吗
Public nudity?
那只是意味着没穿袜子罢了
Eh, that just means going barefoot.
您好
Hello?
戴夫  你好
Hi, Dave.
我是艾米
Uh, it's Amy.
你好吗
Oh. How are you?
我很好  你呢
I'm fine. How are you?
也很好啊  你打来真让我又惊又喜
Terrific. And pleasantly surprised to hear from you,
毕竟上次约会时我的表现不太出色
given how I acted on our last date.
我们俩都有不好的地方嘛
Yeah, well, we both made mistakes, you know.
我吃了最后一根面包棒  你不停提我前任
I took the last breadstick, you gushed over my ex-boyfriend
就像我前任讨论他爱的《星际旅行》演员一样
like he was Leonard Nimoy and you were my ex-boyfriend.
所以今天什么风把你吹来
So, to what do I owe the pleasure?
我有点好奇
Well, I was wondering
你有没有兴趣找个时间再共进晚餐
if you'd like to get dinner again sometime.
好的  没问题
Yes, please.
太好了
Great.
让我看一下行程表  他说道
Let me just check my schedule, he said,
好像他行程表上真有安排一样
trying to seem like a man with things on his schedule.
这周六如何
How 'bout Saturday?
我看看
Uh, hmm...Let me see.
周五跟大牌嘻哈歌手去农贸市场
Uh, Friday, farmers' market with Jay Z.
周日跟歌手艾尔顿·约翰去买钢琴
Sunday, piano shopping with Elton John.
周六行啊
Saturday works.
你知道联合国里
Oh. Did you know, at the United Nations,
有一个外层空间事务部门吗
there's a Department for Outer Space Affairs?
真的吗  为啥要这部门
Really? Why?
以防哪天真有机会跟外星文明接触
They exist in case we ever make contact with an alien civilization.
这种工作大概就是无聊  无聊
Mm, boy, that's one of those jobs that's boring, boring,
无聊到死  突然"哇靠
boring, then, "Oh, God!
我们该怎么做的备忘录放哪去了"
Where's the memo with what we do now?!"
这挺酷
Oh, this is cool.
几周前呢
So, a few weeks ago,
我在脸书上给我们乐团开了个粉丝页...
I set up a fan page on Facebook for our band and...
等等
Wait a second.
你怎么可以不问过我就做这种事
How could you do that without consulting me?
这又不是什么大事
It's not a big deal.
就花五分钟就能弄好的东西
It just took, like, five minutes to set up.
这不是重点
That's not the point.
我们创立"月球足迹"乐团时
When we created Footprints on the Moon,
说好乐团所有决定都得经过两人同意
we agreed that every band decision would be mutual.
你现在就是想独揽一切
Now you're just trying to take over the whole thing.
或许我该单飞
You know, maybe I should go solo.
但有人加了我们的粉丝页
But someone joined our page.
我们有一个粉丝了
We have an actual fan.
好吧  这事比咱俩重要
All right. This thing's bigger than you and me--
乐团重组
band's back together.
你听他写了什么
So, listen to what he wrote.
"我看到你们在漫画店的演出
Uh, "I saw you play at the comic book store.
你们屌爆了"
You guys rock."
然后还有一张笑脸的动图
And then there's a animated smiley face
像嗨到要掀了房顶一样
raising the roof like this...
那晚我们的确是嗨爆了全场
We did raise the roof that night.
绝对啊
Yeah, we totally did.
摇滚明星为啥要嗑药啊  这感觉明明爽炸了
Why do rock stars do drugs when this feels so great?
♪  为何我想不起这首歌 ♪
♪  Why can't I recall this song? ♪
♪  这耗太久了 ♪
♪  This is taking far too long. ♪
♪  这让我想用头撞墙的冲动 ♪
♪  The urge to bang my head against the wall ♪
♪ 撞撞撞  撞了又撞  撞完还撞的感觉强烈 ♪
♪ Again and again and again and again and again is strong. ♪
插上耳机好吗
Put on some headphones.
♪  不要  戴了我耳垂会流汗 ♪
♪  No. They make my earlobes sweat. ♪
亲爱的  你为何不先别想这事
Uh, sweetie, why don't you take a break
先去做点别的事情呢
and do something else for a while?
的确有一个我想着要开始的计划
There was a project I've been thinking about starting.
很好啊  什么计划
Okay, great. What is it?
我让给你看
I'll show you.
致亲爱的未来已疯谢尔顿
Dear Crazy Future Sheldon,
你被卡脑歌给搞疯了
you were driven mad by an earworm.
你的头脑  你曾经最信任的本钱
Your mind, once your most trusted asset,
现在就是浆糊加豆腐渣
is now a sack of parrots and monkeys.
所以
So...
我要告诉你一切你需要知道的事
I'm going to tell you everything you need to know.
首先  音乐非常危险
Uh, first, music is dangerous.
电影《浑身是劲》试图要警告我们
The movie Footloose tried to warn us,
但我们并未听从
but we wouldn't listen.
等等
Oh, wait.
♪  大家解放双... ♪ [电影歌曲]
♪ Everybody cut footloo... ♪
不对
Nope.
我愿意出一千块看你像电影里跳舞
I'll pay $1,000 to watch you cut footloose.
这位是佩妮
This is Penny.
她是你的朋友
She is your friend.
如果她要给你食物  可以放心吃
If she offers you food, it's safe to take it.
反正估计那也是用你自己的钱买的
You probably paid for it, anyway.
你真的要再跟戴夫出去约会吗
So, you're really going out with Dave again?
有何不可
Why not?
他其实是个很好的人啊
He's actually a very nice guy.
但上次整个约会中
But he spent an entire date
他不停地说自己有多爱谢尔顿
talking about how much he loves Sheldon.
谢尔顿也常说他有多爱自己啊
That's nothing Sheldon hasn't done before.
戴夫只是很仰慕他的研究
Dave's just a big fan of his work.
而且他说他不会再提了
Besides, he said he wouldn't bring it up again.
好吧  这次他要带你去哪吃饭
Okay. So where's he taking you?
他会来家里  这次是我要下厨
Oh, he's coming here. I'm actually making dinner.
这是很大的一步啊
Oh. That's a big step.
是吗
It is?
对啊  你邀请他到自己家里来
Yeah. You're inviting him into your home.
这是很亲密的事
It's intimate.
这里可是你小内内的家啊
It's where your underpants live.
其实呢  这样最好
You know what? Good.
我试图要跟谢尔顿重修旧好  他拒绝了我
I tried to get back together with Sheldon; he shot me down;
而戴夫喜欢我
Dave likes me.
或许我需要的就是亲密
Maybe intimate is what I need.
你确定吗
You sure?
你基本都没跟男人亲密过
You've never really been with a man.
你确定要从一个两米的大高个开始吗
Do you really want to start with one that's six-foot-seven?
有何不妥
Why not?
这就像开巴士考驾照  小孩玩大枪啊
'Cause it's like taking your driver's test in a bus.
或许我们该回复我们粉丝的评论  谢谢人家
Maybe we should post a comment back to our fan and thank him.
那我们要回什么
What should we write?
这么回怎么样
How 'bout, uh... Oh, how 'bout,
"或许我们是月球足迹
"We might be Footprints on the Moon,
但你的评论让我们爽得离开月球表面"
but your kind words sent us over the moon."
以后你一定是专煮心灵鸡汤的好奶奶
Someday you're gonna make an amazing grandma.
那你想回什么
What do you want to write?
要回酷一点  就像
Something bad-ass, you know, like...
"感谢知音人
"Thanks for diggin' our vibe.
我们继续摇
We'll keep rockin'
只要你不滚"
if you keep rollin'."
兄弟  如果我有穿着胸罩
Dude, if I was wearing a bra,
现在一定脱下来甩给你了
I'd throw it at your head right now.
我会继续摇  求你千万别
I'll keep rockin'. You don't do that.
好了  我回复了
Okay. I posted it.
这家伙是谁啊
So, who is this guy?
我看看  他叫特伦特·莫纳可
Let's see. Uh, his name is Trent Monaco.
-名字挺酷  -是的
- Cool name. - Yeah.
今年24岁  他是一名DJ
He's 24. He's a deejay.
他自己酿制啤酒  有很酷的纹身
He brews his own beer. He's got awesome tattoos.
兄弟  他还有一个火辣的女友
Dude, he's got a hot girlfriend, too.
靠
Damn.
真不知道我跟他谁才是谁的脑残粉
I don't know if he's our biggest fan or I'm his.
特伦特点赞了我们的回复
Hey, Trent just liked our comment.
他好酷哦
He is so cool!
希望你别介意
No hard feelings,
但我要把我的假想胸罩甩给他了
but I'm throwing my hypothetical bra at him.
老天  他就是不罢休
Oh, my God, he won't stop.
他怎么老能有惹人烦的新招啊
How does he keep coming up with new ways to be annoying?
没人知道  所以他是头号烦人精
Nobody knows. That's why he's number one.
你能去说说他吗
Can you please go talk to him?
拜托  我照顾他一整天了  你去一次
Come on. I take care of him all day long. You do it for once.
什么一次  谁帮他把头发的口香糖弄下来的
Once? Who got the gum out of his hair?
这事还得给你颁奖吗  那可是你的口香糖
What do you want, a medal? It was your gum.
好吧
Fine.
爱你哦
I love you.
去死吧
Who cares?
你来我房间干嘛
What are you doing in my room? I...
住手  那是我的
Stop it! That's mine!
为什么你力大如牛
Why are you so strong?!
问题解决
Problem solved.
对哦  他还有个大号
Oh, yeah, he got a tuba.
致亲爱的未来已疯谢尔顿
Dear Crazy Future Sheldon...
这是恒温器
this is a thermostat.
它能控制公寓的温度
It controls the temperature of the apartment.
理想的温度设置是22摄氏度
The ideal setting is 72 degrees.
如果你觉得这温度冷  那就穿上衣服
If you find this too cold, then put on a jacket.
疯子束身衣好了
A straitjacket,
因为22度最舒服  而且你疯了
'cause 72's the best and you're crazy.
现在介绍  这里
Now... this...
是你的专座
is your spot.
你会死命护住它
You're very protective of it.
一旦有人想坐这里
When anyone else tries to sit here,
你会无情地斥责他们
you berate them relentlessly.
听起来很坏  但你总能让这事变可爱
It sounds mean, but somehow you make it adorable.
人们也对你爱好的恶作剧感到愉悦
People are also delighted by your love of pranks.
比如  莱纳德完全不知道
For example, Leonard has no idea
我对他的咖啡做了什么
what I did to his coffee.
那不是"不含任何咖啡因的咖啡"
It wasn't "Replace it with Folger's crystals,"
我只能透露这么多
I'll tell you that much.
我们能继续工作了吗
Hey, can we please get back to work?
这位是莱纳德
This is Leonard.
他是你全世界最好的朋友
He's your best friend in the world.
好啦  别录了  太可笑了
All right, just stop. This is ridiculous.
有时他会变得暴躁
Sometimes he gets cranky,
但他是值得信赖终身的人
but you can trust him with your life.
而且他为你做的事多到我数不完
And he does more things for you than I can even begin to list.
谢谢
Thank you.
他喝了
Oh, no, he's drinking it.
看看这个
Look at this.
特伦特在组装古董摩托车
Trent is rebuilding a vintage motorcycle.
那真是太酷了
That is so cool!
老旧坏掉的东西远比
Old broken things are so much better
全新能用的赞太多了
than new things that work.
谁是特伦特
Who's Trent?
他是我们的粉丝
Oh, he's our fan.
粉你们什么
Fan of what?
你忘了吗  我俩组了个乐团啊
Did you forget? We're in a band.
就因为你们在漫画店演出过一次吗
You mean because you played one time in the comic book store?
还有儿童医院  虽然最后被人赶走了
And at the children's hospital until they asked us to leave.
兄弟
Hey, dude,
特伦特刚在一家费尔奥克斯的咖啡店签到
Trent just checked in at the coffee shop on Fair Oaks.
真的吗  你想去见见他吗
Really? You want to go down there and meet him?
你们要跟踪人家吗  太变态了吧
Are you stalking him? That's creepy.
那不是变态
It's not creepy.
我创建了我们乐团的主页  特伦特加了进来
I built a Footprints on the Moon fan page, Trent joined it.
在那之后  我只需点开他的个人档案
After that, all I did was check out his profile,
查找他以前发表的东西
go back in the archive of his feed
直到找到他的推特用户名
until I found his Twitter handle.
然后就很容易在照片分享应用上找到他
From there, it was easy to find him on Instagram, Snapchat
接着就能掌握他的一举一动了
and pretty much track his every movement.
如果你觉得这样很变态  那你可真是嫁错人了
So if you think that's creepy, you married the wrong guy.
或许我该嫁给特伦特
Maybe I should marry Trent.
是啊  那也得她泡得到他啊
Yeah, like she could get Trent.
真是太好吃了
This is delicious.
谢谢
Thank you.
我很久没吃过家常饭了
Been a long time since I had a home-cooked meal.
你结婚之后  你的妻子不做饭吗
When you were married, did your wife cook?
一开始不做
Not at first, no.
但在她背着我跟一个法国大厨偷情之后
But when she began cheating on me with a French chef,
她快变成了特级厨师
she became quite the wiz in the kitchen.
也算一丝慰籍吧
So, a little silver lining.
算是吧
I suppose. Yeah.
没有什么比一碗精心调味的法式洋葱汤
Nothing takes the sting out of a shattered life
更能让破碎的生活变得好接受了
like a properly-seasoned bowl of onion soup.
你住在这里多久了
How long have you, uh, lived here?
大概五年了
About five years.
我其实正打算搬去一间更好的公寓
I'm actually thinking of moving to a better place
因为我现在不用住得那么近好去载...
now that I don't need to be so close to...
你懂的
Well, you know.
我懂  那位出色的物理学家
I do. The brilliant physicist
我现在知道他也住附近了  不过我"毫不关心"
that I now know lives in the area, not that I care.
总之  他不开车
Yeah. Anyway, he doesn't drive,
所以他去哪儿基本都得要我载
so, I pretty much had to take him everywhere.
你是逼于无奈  还是三生有幸
Had to or got to?
-抱歉  -我的错
- Sorry. - My fault.
-是我先提他  -是啊
- I brought him up. - Yeah.
我们换个话题吧
Well, let's change the subject.
不要再提那个谁了
No more mentions of you-know-who.
那火车好酷啊
That's a cool train.
你从哪里买的
Where did you get that?
这歌真是根本停不下来啊
This song is never going to stop.
你们遇到过这种烦人无极限的事物吗
Have you ever dealt with something so relentlessly irritating?
这是陷阱题  对吧
That's a trick question, right?
我不应该感到惊讶
Well, I shouldn't be surprised.
历史上有不少的睿智之士最后沦为了疯子
There's a rich history of brilliant minds descending into madness.
拜托  谢尔顿
Come on, Sheldon.
还有好多不是疯子的聪明人呢
There are plenty of smart people who don't have mental problems.
她说得对
Yup, she's right.
这世上每有一个精神病牛顿
For every Newton who had a psychological issue,
就会有一个混蛋爱迪生
there's an Edison who was just a jerk.
这混蛋完全有可能是你嘛
That could totally be you.
恩培多克勒以为他是天神  跳进了火山
Empedocles thought he was a God and jumped into a volcano.
毕达哥拉斯对豆子有莫名的恐惧
And Pythagoras had an irrational fear of beans.
特斯拉疯狂地爱上了一只鸽子
Tesla fell madly in love with a pigeon
还声称那只鸽子也爱他
who he claimed loved him back.
也许是他口袋里有面包
Maybe he just had bread in his pocket.
这个名单可以延伸到科学界之外
The list extends outside of science.
比如像梵高和波洛克那样的画家
Painters like Van Gogh and Pollock,
国际象棋大师鲍比·菲舍尔
chess champion Bobby Fischer,
海滩男孩的布莱恩·威尔森
Brian Wilson of the Beach Boy...
♪ 言语已无法表达 ♪
♪ Know if words could say ♪
♪  但是亲爱的  我会找到方法 ♪
♪  But darlin', I'll find a way ♪
我想起这首歌的名字了
I remember the song!
是"海滩男孩"的《亲爱的》
It's called "Darlin'" by the Beach Boys!
谢天谢地
Oh, thank Goodness!
我不是个疯子
I'm not crazy!
我不用和鸽子结婚了
I don't have to take a pigeon as my bride!
他住屋顶鸽舍的事看来是没指望了
There goes our shot at him living on the roof.
好了  就是他
So, all right, there he is.
我们主动上前自我介绍吗
So, should we introduce ourselves?
别  让他自己发现我们
No! Let him spot us.
他会不会正听着我们的歌呢
I wonder if he's listening to our music right now.
你能想象吗
Could you imagine?
多么酷的见面方式啊
What a cool way for us to meet.
他听着我们的歌  一抬头我们正在他眼前
He's playing our song and looks up, and there we are--
他最爱的原声科幻摇滚二人乐团
his favorite two-piece acoustic sci-fi novelty rock band.
他一定会说
And he's, all, like,
"你们不是月球足迹乐团的..."
"Aren't you the guys from Footprints on the Moo...?"
他在干什么啊
Ooh, what is he doing?!
我看不下去了
I can't watch.
没  没关系
I-I-It's okay.
没关系  他已经抠完了
Oh, it's okay. He's done.
他干嘛要盯着那玩意看
Why is he looking at it?!
他该不会想吃了那玩意吧
Eh, no, he's not going to eat it, is he?
拜托  特伦特  你没这么...
Come on, Trent, you're better than...
我们快走吧
Let's just go.
你们不是...
Hey, aren't you the guys...?
-不是  -从没听说过他们
- Nope! - Never heard of 'em!
♪  言语已无法表达 ♪
♪  Know if words could say ♪
♪  但是亲爱的  我会找到方法 ♪
♪  But darlin', I'll find a way ♪
我好奇为什么偏偏是这首歌
I wonder why it was this particular song
卡在我脑海里
that was stuck in my head.
我也不知道  这歌朗朗上口呀
I don't know. It's pretty catchy.
你有喜欢"海滩男孩"吗
Do you even like the Beach Boys?
他们组合名里有"海滩"两字
They have "Beach" right in the name.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
现在你的注意力又能集中了
Well, now that you can focus again, what do you say
咱们可以回到畴壁表面张力的研究了吧
we get back to surface tension of domain walls?
当然  我已经想到了一个
Of course. I'm already seeing a more efficient way
更高效来...
of taming the ultravi...
我知道为什么我老是忘不掉这歌了
I know why the song was in my head.
为什么
Why?
和艾米有关
It's about Amy.
我知道艾米举止打扮像个老太太
Okay, look, I know Amy's like an old lady,
但她也不至于老到被唱进
but she's not old enough to have a song
一首60年代的歌里吧
from the '60s written about her.
她让我的人生变得更美好
It's about how she made my life better.
想想这歌词吧
Consider the lyrics.
"从前的我灵魂从未完整
"I was living like half a man.
从前的我不会爱  现在的我已会爱
Then I couldn't love, but now I can.
灵魂从此变得完整
More soul than I ever had.
我爱你将我的心变得柔软"
I love the way you soften my life."
她的确让你变得柔软了  不是吗
Well, she did soften your life, didn't she?
没错
Yes!
她就是我的心灵柔顺剂
She's like the dryer sheets of my heart!
我得走了
I have to go.
我也是你的心灵柔顺剂吗
Am I like the dryer sheets of your heart?
不止  你可是我"爱的绒毛清除器"
Better. You're the lint trap of my love.
这个领带夹还挺有趣的
That's an interesting tie clip.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
这是阿伏伽德罗常量
It's, uh, Avogadro's constant.
可以用来计算物质中的原子数
It's useful for calculating the number of atoms in a substance,
或是让每个提问者后悔自己提了这问题
or causing regret in anyone who asks about it.
我...
Oh, I...
我觉得挺不错的
I think it's neat.
对不起  对不起
Sorry. Sorry.
从来没人喜欢过这个领带夹
No one's ever liked the tie clip before,
所以我就失控了
so I just lost all control.
不  没关系  我们本来就在约会
No, it... it's okay, and we are on a date.
我只是有点紧张
I'm... I'm just a little nervous.
你无需对我紧张
Well, no need to be nervous with me.
我只是一个来自异国  人畜无害的巨人
I'm just a harmless giant from a foreign land.
我只是犯傻而已  我...
You know, I'm just being silly. I...
我不知道我还在等什么
I don't know what I'm waiting for.
艾米
Amy?
Amy.
艾米
Amy?
那是谢尔顿
That's Sheldon.
你开玩笑的吧  我头发乱不乱
You're kidding! How's my hair?
谢尔顿  你来的真不凑巧
Sheldon, this-this isn't a good time.
我才不管呢
I don't care.
艾米  有一首歌总是在我脑海盘旋
Amy, there was a song I couldn't get out of my head.
最后我终于发现  这歌和你有关
Eventually, I realized the song was about you,
你是我挥之不去的耳虫  久久盘旋在心口
and like that earworm, I can't get you out of my heart.
所以我想告诉你
So, what I'm trying to say is,
你是我的心虫
you're my heartworm.
这是比喻  不是指真的犬心丝虫
The metaphorical kind, not-not the poodle-killing kind.
你说什么
W-W-W-What?
打扰一下...
If I may...
我觉得他是在用
I believe what he's saying,
一种更诗意更抒情的方式表达
in a charming and delightful way,
他很爱你  希望你能回到他身边
is that he loves you and wants you back.
戴夫·吉布斯  您的铁杆粉丝
Dave Gibbs, huge fan of your work.
不用管我
Don't mind me.
我很抱歉  我不知道你正在约会呢
I'm-I'm sorry. I didn't realize you were on a date.
不  没关系  你继续说
No, it-it... it's okay. Keep going?
艾米  如果你愿意重新做我的女朋友
Amy, if you want to be my girlfriend again,
我也非常愿意做你的男朋友
I really want to be your boyfriend.
我非常愿意
I really want that, too.
太好了  因为我爱你
Good. Because I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
快亲她呀  你这个聪明的大傻瓜
Kiss her, you brilliant fool!
我就不打扰你约会了
I'll let you get back to your date.
给我回来
Get back here!
♪  亲爱的 ♪
♪  Oh, oh, oh, darlin' ♪
♪  我总是反复梦到你  亲爱的美人儿 ♪
♪  I dream about you often, my pretty darlin' ♪
♪  我爱你将我的心变得柔软... ♪
♪  I love the way you soften my... ♪
好了
Okay, then.
那我就自己走了
I'll, uh, see myself out.
艾米  谢谢你的晚餐
Amy, thank you for dinner.
库珀博士  非常高兴见到您
Dr. Cooper, pleasure to meet you, sir.
如果下次您有空
Uh, if perhaps sometime you have a spare moment,
我非常愿意和您讨论一下物理问题
I'd, uh, love-love to discuss physics,
或是按你们的说法  一起"侃大山"
or "shoot the breeze," as you Yanks say.
真是美好的一晚啊
What a lovely evening.